my name is Aaron Cairo I'm a sponsored
skateboarder from the San Francisco Bay
area and today I'm going to teach you
guys how to Olie while
writing so this is the very most basic
thing there is really and the big point
that I want to make here is that you
should get really really really good at
writing I want to have a huge emphasis
on that cuz there is a big emphasis in
skateboarding already on learning to do
tricks and you can get a little bit
confused of like let's just learn to do
all the tricks but
it's very important to not miss the most
basic part which is riding and a lot of
people think oh yeah I can step on my
board and push and I can ride and yeah
we do have the how to push tutorial for
sure I want to go into how much time you
should spend on that step because it's
super super super important so you
should be able to ride down the street
and cruise around I know in this footage
I'm doing some all off curves and stuff
you don't necessarily have to be able to
do that cuz this is the tutorial to
learn how to do that but this is kind of
the direction you're going cuz after you
learn this this is what you want to be
able to do you want to be able to just
cruise down the street pop up and down
the curbs and roll and it's really
really really fun to just be able to do
that you got to think with that just
rolling around and cruising is so much
fun it's incredible so in learning to
ride it's not just like you push on your
skateboard and that's it you want to be
able to turn both
directions with a carving turn and also
a kick turn a kick turn is where you
lift up the front truck and move it so
you want to be able to do all of those
variations of both sides of the turn you
want to be able to turn the front
Direction and turn the back Direction
just cuz you're going to need to be able
to move around so huge emphasis on the
writing the better you get at the
writing the better you're going to be
able to do every single one of your
tricks so don't make that a short step
make it a very long step if anything
cool so obviously all of the regular
Allie steps apply so here's the foot
position your front foot is just a
little bit back from those bolts pretty
straight your back foot with the ball of
your foot is on the edge of the tail you
want it just right there so you can pop
straight down you'll be popping straight
down with the back foot drag that front
foot up and then
forward just like I said it's all of the
same stuffs from the OE it's basically
just another variation of the Olie
tutorial you're going to be popping your
tail popping your tail popping your tail
dragging your front foot up dragging
your front foot up
so then after that it's going to be the
pop the drag and then the you're going
to be pushing your front foot forward so
you'll drag your front foot up and then
it'll go forward drag your front foot up
and then it'll go forward that forward
motion is what levels your board out in
the air so you want to make sure that
that is part of the motion that you do
with your foot it's all one motion but
it is like pop drag forward and that's
what levels you out and then you drop
down very very important very good so
definitely definitely learn all of those
steps it's a very important piece cool
so once you've got that down and it is
good to learn that stationary what I
suggest is then you start with just
moving a little bit just go at a little
rate of speed poping olly and then you
can go a little bit faster and a little
bit faster and a little bit faster until
you're starting to get it going like at
a good rate of speed now again if you're
really really good at writing your board
and you can cruise down the street and
you've gotten real comfortable with that
you're riding to the store you're riding
to school the more you're on your board
the better cuz the more comfortable you
are with your board the easier all of
these tricks are going to be to learn
don't think with like oh I'm have to go
back and learn how to ride better no
just think with like oh I'm riding my my
board down the street like when you see
some of these very best skaters they do
these lines that are incredible but you
can tell that they are so comfortable on
their board it's like an extension of
their feet it's like they're more
comfortable on their skateboard than
they are walking and that's the place
that you want to get to and the way that
you get there is ride your board all the
time ride it everywhere so once you get
comfortable allly wall riding you're
going to then like go well I can ollie
now I want to ollie over something so
put an obstacle Out start with like a
small obstacle start with a crack start
with something that you're not going to
fall if you don't make it and then just
practice that and then put out here we
got this little sandbag we'll toss this
out here boom there we go and then
you're going to roll up to it as a
practice step you can all it to the side
of it your friend can tell you whether
or not you made it and you can just
practice that and check it out check it
out see if you can ollie high enough and
then when you're ready you're going to
roll up to the obstacle keep your eyes
on the obstacle it's very important
sometimes people like kind of miss that
step or they're watching their board too
much and then they miss their timing cuz
the timing is very important otherwise
you're just going to run into the
obstacle and fall over right so eyes on
the obstacle roll up to it and then when
you're just about to it you're going to
pop the board drag your front foot up
and then your front foot comes forward
that's going to level your board out in
the air and then you're going to drop
your board down boom land and then roll
away so that's the Aly wall
riding spend a lot of time on this
specifically spend a lot of time riding
your board around and then the more you
just spend alling over things the better
so once you get that then you start
going into some other tricks and then
skating is more fun and more fun and
more fun and more fun and more fun it's
fun from day one but the more tricks you
can do it's even more fun great so with
your feet in the Olie position you've
gotten yourself pushing you're rolling
you're looking at the obstacle so you're
watching it as it comes forward because
you're rolling towards it so it's coming
closer to you and then you're going to
bend down
and as you come up you're going to pop
your back foot drag your front foot
forward on the board you got to make
sure it scrapes on that part of your
shoe your shoe better be wearing a hole
that's part of skateboarding you drag
that front foot up and then you push it
forward that forward motion is what
levels your board out in the air as your
your knees are going to be crouched at
this point and then you're going to
start just gradually bringing your knees
down I call it the landing gear put your
landing gear down land hand and then
roll away that's the full oi wall moving
and just remember it's so important you
have to get really really good at riding
so don't skimp on riding your board just
ride the board everywhere super super
important I want to make sure you guys
really get that down in order to get
over something you are going to be
looking at the obstacle so you might
want to do a few allies or practice the
Allies enough to get this really down
while you're not looking at your board
cuz if you're so concentrated on having
to look at your board then it's going to
throw you off cuz you're going to need
to look at the obstacle not your board
so you got to kind of be able to do the
ollie while you're not looking at your
board so think with that as a part of
going over something as well for the
full basics of skateboarding I did make
a very very complete video um it's
really good because it is a full program
it's like you start at step one go to
step two 3 4 5 up to all the way through
the full Basics which are Oli front side
180 back side 180 pop shove front shove
he flip kickflip that full length video
is called skateboarding made simple it
is available at brail skateboarding.com
and it is very very very good and very
detailed it's also available on iTunes
for your iPhone and Google Play for your
Android devices so there's six volumes
of that video and it goes up to very
very difficult tricks so definitely
check it out you won't be
[Music]
disappointed thanks for watching tell us
in the comments what tricks you guys are
trying to learn we want to do at least
one tutorial every week and we want to
keep these rolling we want to keep you
guys learning on your board we know
we're doing some of the tutorials again
just let us know what tricks you guys
are trying to learn we'll do our best to
help you thanks for watching you guys
are the best we really really appreciate
it please subscribe click that like
button and remember the comments below
[Music]